Guide to the Joseph Urban Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series VI: Set Models
  - Jonny Spielt Auf
    - Act I Sc 2 -- Act II Sc 2 -- Anita's Room -- Act I Sc 3/4 Corridor Scene -- Act II Sc 5 Railroad Station -- Act II Sc 6 Street Scene -- Act II Sc 8 Finale -- Act II Sc 4 Street Scene -- Act I Sc 1 and Act II Sc 3 Palace Hotel (Glacier), Met, 1/19/29
      [One scene rehoused. Original Housing: 8 Bundles plus Carton 33]
  - Jonny Spielt Auf
    - Act II Sc 5 Railroad Station, Met, 1/19/29, (6 boxes, 1 carton)
      [Renovated for exhibit. Original Housing: 8 Bundles plus Carton 33]
  - Juive, La [The Jewess]
    - Act IV Sc 2, Met, 11/22/19
      [Untouched. Original Housing: 1 bundle ]
  - King's Henchman
    - Act I -- Act II -- Act III -- Act II, Forest -- Act II, Met, 2/17/27
      [Untouched. Original Housing: 5 Bundles ]
  - Lohengrin
    - Acts I, II, III, Met, 2/6/21
      [Untouched. no models; sketches]
  - Louisa Miller
    - Terrace sc., Act II, interior; Act III (not used); Act IV, Living Room scene, Met, 12/21/29
      [Untouched. Original Housing: 4 bundles plus Carton 14]
  - Louise
    - Acts I & IV, Garret room; Street sc.; Act II, Sc.2, Sewing room; Act III, garden sc., Met, 3/1/29
      [Untouched. Original Housing: four bundles]
  - Macbeth
    - Unknown, Theater, 2/7/16
      [Untouched. Original Housing: 1 bundle]
  - Madam Pompadour[?]
    - [Ziegfeld Follies?] Act III (not used)
  - Madama Butterfly
    - Border #1, Act I, Met, 11/24/22
  - Manon
    - Act III -- Act IV, Gambling Room, Met, 12/22/28
      [Untouched. Original Housing: 2 bundles]
  - Melody
    - Act I: Jess Scene -- Act II London Mall Drop[?] -- Act IIIJolly Miller Inn Drop[?], Theater, 2/14/33
      [Untouched. Original Housing: 1 unidentified bundle]
  - Merry Wives of Windsor
    - Street Scene, Theater, 3/20/16
  - Norma
    - Act I -- Act II -- Act III, Met, 11/16/27
      [Untouched. Original Housing: 3 bundles plus carton 13]
  - Oberon
    - Unknown, Met, 12/28/18
  - Palm Beach Girls [Palm Beach Nights]
    - Umbrella Scene -- Red Gauze Scene (not used) -- Patio Scene -- Oriental Scene(not used) -- Golden Palm Tree Scene -- Oriental Scene -- Cabaret Scene, Ziegfeld, 1/4/26
      [Untouched. Original Housing: 7 bundles ]
  - Pelleas et Melisande
    - Tracings[?], Met, 3/21/25
  - Peter Ibbetson
    - Act IV Sc 4 Opera box scene -- Act III Sc 1 Colonel's Room -- Glade Scne and Chaplain's Room -- Act III Sc 1/3; Act II Sc 2 -- Act III Sc 5 -- Act III Sc 2/3, Met, 2/7/32
      [Untouched. Original Housing: six bundles]
  - Polly
    - Club Reception Room -- Aviation -- Long Island R.R. Stattion and Casino Scene, Theater, 1/8/29
      [Untouched. Original Housing: three bundles]
  - Pom Pom
    - Unknown, Theater, 2/28/16
  - Princess Charming
    - Miscellaneous pieces, Theater, 10/13/30
      [One scene rehoused. Original Housing: Cartons 16-18]
  - Princess Charming
    - Bedroom, Theater, 10/13/30
      [Renovated for exhibit, 2000. Original Housing: Cartons 16-18]
  - Prophete [Propheta]
    - Unknown, Met, 2/7/18
  - Restless Sex
    - Garden of Paradise prologue, Film, 1920
      [Untouched. Original Housing: one bundle. -- Formerly filed under Adam and Eve, but GC believes this to be the setting for the live action prologue to Restless Sex, or, possibly, a Follies number.]
  - Rio Rita
    - Courtyard of a Mexican mansion, Ziegfeld, 2/2/27, (1 carton)
      [Renovated for exhibit, 2000.]
  - Rio Rita
    - Cave Scene -- Inn Scene -- Wedding Scene -- Ship Scene, Ziegfeld, 2/2/27
      [One scene renovated. Original Housing: 4 bundles plus carton 21]
  - Ripples [Fred Stone Show]
    - Extras -- Cottage Drop -- Finale Scene -- Ball Room Scene -- Hudson River Scene -- Trouper's Room Scene -- Fianl Scene(not used) -- Mountain Scene -- In Front of Inn Scene -- Curtain -- State Trooper and House Drop, Thetare, 2/11/30
      [Untouched. Original Housing: 11 bundles]
  - Romeo et Juliette
    - Prologue, Met, 11/25/22
  - Rondine, La
    - Act I -- Act II -- Act III, Met, 3/10/28
      [Untouched. Original Housing: two bundles plus one oversized bundle]
  - Rosalie
    - Act II Drops in One -- Romanze Scene -- Kings Club Scene, Ziegfeld, 1/10/28
      [Untouched. Original Housing: three bundles plus one unidentified--Cartons 31 - 32]
  - Schwanda
    - Door to city, Met, 11/7/31
      [Untouched. Original Housing: one oversized bundle -- s.a. Follies n.d., Misc. pieces]
  - Show Girl
    - Stage Door Act II Sc 3 (not used) -- Drop In One -- Simple Simon -- Kissing/Forest (shelved at end in one bundle) -- Castle Scene -- Minstrel Scene -- Act I Sc 5 Street Sc (not used) -- Act I Sc 6 Night Club Sc -- Act II Sc 32 Paris Sc (and 5 small sc's) -- Act II Sc 2 Stage Door (full se) -- Act II Sc 5 Dressing Room -- Simple Simon -- Coney Island Sc -- Act I Sc 1/2 Colonial House -- Simple Simon -- City Wall Drop -- King Cole's Hall -- Dungeon Scene, Ziegfeld, 7/2/29
      [Untouched. Original Housing: 14 bundles plus carton 41 -- n.b. For Show Girl and Simple Simon consult inventory list of 8/79" -- Simple Simon is a separate Ziegfeld show, grouped in here.]
  - Showboat
    - Unknown, Ziegfeld, 12/27/27
      [Untouched. Original Housing: carton 42 -- "See: Follies n.d. Misc. pieces"]
  - Simple Simon
    - Unknown, Ziegfeld, 2/18/30
      [Currently mixed in with Show Girl bundles]
  - Smiles
    - Dock Scene -- Bremen Scene (both in on bundle) -- FInal Act 2 and Curtain (not used) -- Red Room Scene -- Paris Scene -- FInal Act I -- Opening Scene -- Mary Pickford/Golf Course Scene (one bundle) -- 2 Bar Rooms (not used) -- Finale Act !, Ziegfeld, 11/18/30
      [One scene rehoused. Original Housing: 9 bundles]
  - Smiles
    - Cafe le Berry, Ziegfeld, 11/18/30, (1 carton)
  - Song of Flame
    - Act I Sc 1 -- Act I Sc 1 Block Sc -- Act I Sc 1 Street Sc -- Act I Sc 1 Gate of Castle -- Act I Sc 5 Hall in Palace -- Act II Sc 1 Room in Pension -- Act II Sc 3 Cafe -- Act II Sc 2 and 4 Outside of Cafe -- Act II Sc 5 Green Room -- Act II Sc 6 Epilogue, Theater, 12/30/25
      [Untouched. Original Housing: 10 bundles]
  - Sonnambula
    - Count's Room -- Forest Scene -- In Front of Mill Scene, Met, 3/16/32
      [Untouched. Original Housing: 3 bundles]
  - Sons o' Guns [Tin Hats]
    - Road Scene -- Procession Scene, Theater, 11/26/29
      [One scene rehoused. Original Housing: 2 bundles]
  - Sons o' Guns [Tin Hats]
    - Act 2.8: Ballroom, Theater, 11/26/29, (2 boxes)
  - Tale of the Wolf
    - Dream Scene -- Act II Boudoir[?], Theater, 10/7/25
  - Thais
    - Boudoir Scene -- Convent Scene -- Act III sc 2, Met, 12/14/22
  - Three Musketeers
    - Queen's Chamber -- Garden Scene -- Act II Sc of Ballroom -- Hotel de Ville Paris, Ziegfeld, 3/13/28
      [Untouched. Original Housing: 3 bundles [last two scenes in one bundle]]
  - Treasure Girl [Gertrude Lawrence]
    - Curtain and Portal, Ziegfeld Follies, 11/8/28, (1 box)
      [Rehoused 2000 -- s.a. Follies n.d. Misc. pieces]
  - Treasure Girl [Gertrude Lawrence]
    - Ocean, Ziegfeld Follies, 11/8/28, (2 boxes boxes)
      [Rehoused 2000. -- s.a. Follies n.d. Misc. pieces]
  - Treasure Girl [Gertrude Lawrence]
    - Garden, Ziegfeld Follies, 11/8/28, (2 bxoes)
  - Treasure Girl [Gertrude Lawrence]
    - Interior, Ziegfeld Follies, 11/8/28, (2 boxes)
  - Treasure Girl [Gertrude Lawrence]
    - Jungle, Ziegfeld Follies, 11/8/28, (3 boxes)
  - Treasure Girl [Gertrude Lawrence]
    - Beach, Ziegfeld Follies, 11/8/28, (3 boxes)
  - Tristan und Isolde
    - Act I Curtain No.'s 4,5,6,7, Theater- Met, 11/20/20
  - Turandot
    - (Steps not used) -- Act II Sc 1 -- Act III Sc 2 -- Act I -- Act III -- Act I -- unidentified Sc, Theater, 11/24/14
      [Untouched. Original Housing: 4 bundle plus cartons 1 -3]
  - Vestale, La
    - Act II -- Act II (not used) -- Act III sc 1, Met, 11/12/25
      [Untouched. Original Housing: 3 bundles ]
  - Walkure
    - Rocky pass sc (not used) -- Interior Act I (not used) -- Mountain Top Sc (not used), [n.p.], [n.d.]
      [Untouched. Original Housing: 3 bundles plus carton 30]
  - Whoopee
    - Eddie Cantor (carton 44) -- Tent Scene (carton 45) -- Eddie Cantor Ziegfeld Scene (Carton 46), Ziegfeld, 12/4/28
      [Untouched. Original Housing: Cartons 44-46]
  - Whoopee
    - Adobe Mission with Bells (carton 43), Ziegfeld, 12/4/28
      [Renovated for exhibit, 2000. Original Housing: Cartons 43-46]
  - Wild Rose [Hawthorne of the U.S.A.]
    - Act I Sc 1: Casino -- Act I Sc 2: Drop eith Window -- Act I Sc 3: Interior Inn -- Act I Sc 4: Garden Wall Scene -- Act I Sc 5: Palace Garden -- Act II Sc 1: Interior of Palace -- Act II Sc 2: Courtyard of Palace -- Act II Sc 3/5: Border Line -- Act II Sc 4 Tower Room -- Act II Sc 6: Hall in Palace, Theater, 1/20/26
      [Untouched. Original Housing:. Ten Bundles]
  - Yours Truly
    - Cabaret Scene -- Mission Scene -- Garden Scene -- Chinatown Scene -- Subterranean Scene, Theater, 1/25/27
      [Untouched. Original Housing:. 5 bundles]
  - Ziegfeld Follies 1923
    - Kid Boots Plam Beach Sc -- Swanee River Sc, Ziegfeld, 10/20/23
      [Untouched. Original Housing:. 2 bundles]
  - Ziegfeld Follies 1924
    - Garden Sc, Louis XIV, Cowboy Sc., Ziegfeld, 6/24/24
      [Untouched. Original Housing:. 3 bundles]
  - Ziegfeld Follies 1924 [Lew Fields Follies]
    - Merry-Go-Round, Con Boys sc., Ziegfeld, [6/24/24]
      [One scene rehoused]
  - Ziegfeld Follies 1924 [Lew Fields Follies]
    - Merry-Go-Round, Ziegfeld, 6/24/24], (2 boxes)
      [Partially rehoused, 2000 (needs redoing)]
  - Ziegfeld Follies 1927
    - Cotton Field Sc -- House of Glass -- Jungle Jingle -- Grand Staircase (carton 57; refurbished), Ziegfeld, 8/16/27
      [Untouched. Original Housing:. 3 bundles in one box plus carton 57]
  - Ziegfeld Follies 1931
    - Theater Scene -- Rainbow Gauze Drops -- Hollywood Sc -- Curtains (not used) -- Penthouse Sc -- Jungle Sc -- Observatory Sc -- Portal and Rainbow Gauze Drops -- Empire State Bldg Sc -- Island Sc and Trade House Sc -- Finale 1 (not used) -- Cabaret Mission Sc (not used) -- Bridge Sc -- Political Club (not used) -- Portal (not used) -- Opening Scene - Sunset Scene (not used) -- Band Sc (not used) -- Island Sc (not used) -- Restaurant Sc -- B. Room Sc -- B and D Sc -- Buckingham Palace Sc -- Finale -- Speakeasy Sc -- Swanee River Sc -- Portal -- Grand Hotel --, Ziegfeld, 7/1/31
      [Untouched. Original Housing:. 28 bundles -- Carton 36: Follies/Whoopee -- Carton 35: Ziegfeld Follies/Scandles/Empire State Bldg -- Carton 38: Follies Street Sc -- Carton 39: Follies Blue Nursery -- Carton 40: Follies n.d.]
  - Ziegfeld Follies n.d.
    - Misc. pieces including pieces from The Gertrude Lawrence Show; Schwanda; and Showboat (maybe), Ziegfeld
      [Untouched. Original Housing: ]
  - Ziegfeld Theater
    - Apron and Proscenium, Arch and Design, 1926, (1 carton)
      [Renovated for exhibit, 2000. carton 56]